

Tanyaradzwa Rodgers Ngara

PhD student, Biomedical Engineering

A highly enthusiastic and motivated research scientist with a professional attitude who enjoys being part of a team and working to make it successful and productive. I grasp new ideas and concepts quickly and am innovative as well as creative in thinking up solutions to problems.

🔀 tanyaradzwangara@outlook.com

+8615623830252

Wuhan, China

www.researchgate.net/profile/Tanyaradzwa-Ngara-2

linkedin.com/in/tanyaradzwa-rodgers-ngara

SKILLS

Writing

Research Techniques

CSS

Web Developmen

4olecular Biotechnoloau

Recent Advances in Biopharmaceuticals

Soft Lithography

Droplet Microfluidics

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Biomedical Engineering

Huazhong University of Science and Technology

09/2019 - Present

Relevant Coursework

Progress in Biomaterials and Tissue Engineering

Master of Science (MSc), Biomedical Engineering

Huazhong University of Science and Technology

02/2017 - 01/2019

Relevant Coursework

- Advanced Biomaterials
- Plant Proteomics
- Principles of Bioengineering

- Tissue Engineering
- Bioenergy
- Advanced Medical Biology

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Chairperson

Twimbos Giving Hope

01/2016 - 01/2017 A voluntary club made up of Zimbabwean Twitter users across the globe to help the needy in Zimbabwe

Gweru, Zimbabwe

Wuhan, China

Wuhan, China

Committee Member

OneURGE

06/2015 - 01/2017 Environmental awareness on Global Warming Climate Change Gweru, Zimbabwe

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Development of Databases for the Biodegradation of Pollutants in Wastewater (09/2019 - Present)

Conducted an academic research project to design relational databases, web interfaces, and the development of online searching mechanisms for the analysis of microbial communities capable of degrading different types of pollutants found in wastewater.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Design, fabrication and characterization of microfluidic chips used for the production of monodisperse double emulsions (02/2017 - 01/2019)

Conducted an academic research project to assess the impact of surface modified polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS) microfluidic devices in the generation of water-in-oil-in-water (W/O/W) double emulsions.

PUBLICATIONS

Review article

Recent Advances in Function-based Metagenomic Screening

December 2018

Research article

mibPOPdb An online database for microbial biodegradation of persistent organic pollutants August 2022 Research article

Biological Nitrogen Removal Database: A Manually Curated Data Resource

February 2022

WORK EXPERIENCE

Agricultural Biotechnology Researcher

Agri-biotech Pvt Ltd

08/2015 - 01/2017 Harare, Zimbabwe

Using biotechnology techniques in development of disease-free, drought-resistant, high-yielding varieties of traditional crops such as cassava. Achievements/Tasks

- Conducting research projects focused on tissue culture of root and tuberous crops
- Regeneration and transformation of various crops include maize, cotton and potato
- Experiments to attempt cotton (Gossypium hirsutum L.) regeneration via somatic embryogenesis
- Identification and Characterization of Cassava Mosaic Virus based on coat protein

HONOR AWARDS

HUST Academic Excellence Award (01/2021 - Present)

Huazhong University of Science and Technology

INTERESTS

Volunteering and community involvement Re

Reading

History

Listening to music

LANGUAGES

English



Shona



Chinese



REFERENCES

Prof Houjin Zhang

Contact: hjzhang@hust.edu.cn - +861587145360

Dr J. Ndlovu, Senior Lecturer

Contact : jndlovu@cut.ac.zw - +263771305713